Center for International Environment and Resource Policy Records UA228
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Center for International Environment and Resource Policy Records
1990 -- 2012
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Center for International Environment and Resource Planning
UA228
4.8 Linear Feet 4 boxes
This collection contains records created by the Center for International Environment and Resource Policy.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trustees records are open for research.
This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in 2 series: Office files, and Unprocessed accessions.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records created by the Center for International Environment and Resource Policy, including grant applications, correspondence, presentations, event records, meeting notes, reports, clippings, publications, and internship program materials.
Biographical / Historical
The Center for Environment and Resource Policy (CIERP) was created as part of the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy in 1992 "to meet the growing need for international environmental leaders". The Center conducts scholarly research to provide empirical evidence that informs environmental and developmental policy, with the goal of promoting environmental sustainability worldwide. In addition to conducting research, it educates future policy makers in how to interpret environmental research and how to draft and implement environmentally sound policy.
The Center was founded by Professor of Environmental Policy William Moomaw. Moomaw, a former Chemistry professor, headed the Center from its founding in 1992 until his retirement in 2013. He was replaced by Kelly Gallagher, who graduated from the CIERP program in 2000. Gallagher took a leave of absence in 2014-2015 to serve as a Senior Policy Advisor to the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, before re-assuming her role as director at the Center in the fall of 2015. Under Gallagher, the Center for Environment and Resource Policy has taken an interdisciplinary approach to its mission, focusing on "shifting global development onto a path that is more environmentally, socially, and economically sustainable".
The Center for Environment and Resource Policy regularly hosts seminars and conferences, and in 2007 launched the IDEAS journal of student research, which ran through 2011. In 2019, IDEAS was revived as an online journal, offering students the ability to publish short papers on topics relating to energy innovation. In 2016, following the international Paris Climate Agreement of the preceding year, the Center for Environment and Resource policy created the Climate Policy Lab, which brings together teams of researchers located around the globe to empirically evaluate climate policies for effectiveness. The Climate Policy lab works through a comparative international analysis to evaluate the effectiveness of already-implemented climate policy worldwide. It publishes its results, as well as holds workshops and trainings, in order to advance global understanding of environmental regulation and policy.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Centers and Institutes; Research and Research Administration
- Office files, 1990 -- 2012; UA228.001; 4.8 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records of CIERP research, projects, events, fundraising, and publicity.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by subject.
  Conditions Governing Access
  20 years from date of creation.
  - Office files, 1992 -- 2005; UA228.001.001 (Box 1)
    Includes records related to the Kyoto conference, publicity, Fellows, the web, projects, environmental resources, internships, grant research, events, and the academic tech grant.
  - Events, 1990 -- 2012; UA228.001.002 (Box 2)
    Includes event records related to CIERP meet & greets (speakers, ECI research seminars, SDD roundtables, Maurice Segal Lecture Series, and conferences); and the Tufts-Soviet agreement (Global classroom/satellite hook-up and student exchange).
  - Fundraising, 1995-2005; International forest research, 2002-2007, UA228.001.003 (Box 3)
  - Projects, 2006 -- 2010; UA228.001.004 (Box 4)
    Documented projects include the Solar Decathalon, MBRS (Meso-American Reefs), Packard Foundation (economics of nitrogen flows), NSF (nitrogen), CLI Suriname, Forest Financing Mechanism (Dutch grant), Distributed Energy, and Lauder (carbon sequestration).
- Additional accessions, 1994 -- 1999; UA228.002; 2 Digital Object(s)
  - 1999 CIERP Retreat, UA228.002.00001; 4 Digital Object(s)
  - Foes over Fish, 1994; UA228.002.00003; 16 Digital Object(s)
- Publications and reports, 2005; UA228.000011; 0.1 Linear Feet; 1 Digital Object(s)
  Open for research.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains publications and reports by the Center for International Environment and Resource Policy.
  - Cold Chain Report, 2005; UA228.002.00002; 4 Digital Object(s)
  - Prospects for Reducing Carbon Intensity in China, by Xuan Xiaowei and Kelly Sims Gallagher, 2014 February; UA228.000012 (Box Shared 145, Folder 6)
    General
    Number 008